(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-03T12:58:25.018658",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
はれはれ 今踊り踊れ
Rejoice, dance and dance right now!
恋い焦がれ遊べ
Play with burning passion,
咲乱れて歌え
Bloom in chaos and sing out!
羽織舞え 今踊り戻せ
Let robes dance, bring back the dance,
吸気に遊べ
Play with style,
さあ ここで踊れ
Come on, dance right here!
ひゅるりらぱっぱ
Hyururira pappa
初めようか 鼓動が過ぎてく
Shall we begin? My heartbeat races on,
よりどりみどり様に繁し
Abundant and colorful in every way.
あんなこれも かご放り込み
Tossing those and this into the basket too,
欲にまみれ 生きていたい
I want to live wallowing in desires.
人生より道回り道生きたいように生きな晴れや
Wandering through life's detours, living just as I want—let it be bright!
はれはれ 今踊り踊れ
Rejoice, dance and dance right now!
恋い焦がれ遊べ
Play with burning passion,
咲乱れて歌え
Bloom in chaos and sing out!
羽織舞え 今踊り戻せ
Let robes dance, bring back the dance,
吸気に遊べ
Play with style,
さあ ここで踊れ
Come on, dance right here!
ひゅるりらぱっぱ ひゅるりらぱっぱ
Hyururira pappa, hyururira pappa
初めようか 鼓動が過ぎてく
Shall we begin? My heartbeat races on,
さあ水も甘いも祭り囃子
Come now, both sweet and bitter festival music,
味わい尽くしてしまいましょ
Let's taste it all to the very end,
さあ 何から平らげよ
Now, what shall we devour first?
人生気づけば 야の如し
Before you know it, life passes like an arrow,
命の花を打ち上げましょう
Let's fire off the flowers of life!
はれはれ 今踊り踊れ
Rejoice, dance and dance right now!
恋い焦がれ遊べ
Play with burning passion,
咲乱れて歌え
Bloom in chaos and sing out!
羽織舞え 今踊り戻せ
Let robes dance, bring back the dance,
吸気に遊べ
Play with style,
さあ ここで踊れ
Come on, dance right here!
ひゅるりらぱっぱ ひゅるりらぱっぱ
Hyururira pappa, hyururira pappa
花よ花よ誇りなさい
Flowers, oh flowers, be proud,
迷うことなく君のまま
Without hesitation, just as you are,
上を向いてごらんなさい
Look up towards the sky,
最後の日まで奏でやれ
Play music proudly until your very last day!
はれはれ 今踊り踊れ
Rejoice, dance and dance right now!
恋い焦がれ遊べ
Play with burning passion,
咲乱れて歌え
Bloom in chaos and sing out!
羽織舞え 今踊り戻せ
Let robes dance, bring back the dance,
吸気に遊べ
Play with style,
さあ ここで踊れ
Come on, dance right here!
はれはれ 今踊り踊れ
Rejoice, dance and dance right now!
誰それがお手を元の世界に夢中
Who's obsessed with the world right at hand
化け物の飼い方を学んでる
Learning how to tame a monster
選ばれるためなら舌を売る
You’d sell your own tongue if that would get you chosen
裏切られた分だけ墓を掘る
Digging as many graves as you’ve been betrayed
へらへらのおつむがどうにかして
Brainless head trying its hardest
うすうす寒い言葉ばかりになる
Cringe-worthy words overflow
ねえ、
Hey,
あんた
you
わかんないねえ
really don’t get it...
誰それがお手を元の世界に夢中
Who's obsessed with the world right at hand
化け物の飼い方を学んでる
Learning how to tame a monster
選ばれるためなら舌を売る
You’d sell your own tongue if that would get you chosen
裏切られた分だけ墓を掘る
Digging as many graves as you’ve been betrayed
へらへらのおつむがどうにかして
Brainless head trying its hardest
うすうす寒い言葉ばかりになる
Cringe-worthy words overflow
覚ええない顔とバイバイできるなら
If bye-byes can be said to such a facade
阿修羅にだってなれるわ
I can turn into Ashura
逃げるすけすけすけすけぷっ
Run away, escape, escape, escape
仏のまま
as Buddha
飛べるすけすけすけすけぷっ
I can fly, step, step, step
仰せのまま
as you wish
アンダスタン アンダスタン
Understand, understand,
どーどー閻魔様さえ呑ーくって
even the devil can be devoured
騙すすけーくすけーくすけーく
Cheat, sneak, sneak, sneak
嵐の中
in a storm
跳ねるすけっぴすけっぴすけっぴ あっそ、へのかっぱ
Prance, skip, skip, skip oh really, who cares?
アンダスタン アンダスタン
Understand,
いっそ骨の髄までしゃぶって
might as well bleed them dry
日々の浸みを木々に焼いて温をり合う
Burning the oozing titbits of everyday life and basking in its warmth
義理を誘った彼の四肢は散り散りになる
He who defied obligation has his four limbs torn apart
知りもせずに意味を美意識だと崇める
Finding worth in an aesthetic value without comprehending
擬似餌じみた執拗さに御の字だった
Couldn’t be happier with a compulsion akin to an artificial lure
愉悦な御頼のフルコースにうわべの面をして可愛がっていた
A hilarious full course meal of pontifications showed superficial affection
くだらない僧と踊るくらいなら悪魔と手を繋ぐわ
If I have to dance with a good-for-nothing priest, I’d rather hold the devil’s hand
逃げるすけすけすけすけぷっ 仏のまま
Run away, escape, escape, escape as Buddha
飛べるすけすけすけすけぷっ 仰せのまま
I can fly, step, step, step as you wish
アンダスタン アンダスタン 阿鼻地獄の果てまでロックオン
Understand, locking on until the ends of Avici hell
騙すすけーくすけーくすけーく 嵐の中
Cheat, sneak, sneak, sneak in a storm
跳ねるすけっぴすけっぴすけっぴ あっそ、へのかっぱ
Prance, skip, skip, skip oh really, who cares?
アンダスタン アンダスタン あんた寝言はあの世で言って
Understand, save your silly talk for the afterlife
逃げるすけすけすけすけぷっ 仏のまま
Run away, escape, escape, escape as Buddha
飛べるすけすけすけすけぷっ 仰せのまま
I can fly, step, step, step as you wish
アンダスタン アンダスタン どーどー閻魔様さえ呑ーくって
Understand, even the devil can be devoured
騙すすけーくすけーくすけーく 嵐の中
Cheat, sneak, sneak, sneak in a storm
跳ねるすけっぴすけっぴすけっぴ あっそ、へのかっぱ
Prance, skip, skip, skip oh really, who cares?
アンダスタン アンダスタン いっそ骨の髄までしゃぶって
Understand, might as well bleed them dry
ねえ、ギャーギャー言っちゃって
Hey, squawking so loudly
頭を垂れないで
Stop bowing your head to everyone
Yo, yo, yo, yo, yo!
What's up! I am Chaos, the end of days!
A stray rat trapped in a cage, or I should say, your best friend!
Bae takes us from Hololive English!
What do you call... What is the end...
氷の檻に封印されし漆黒のバラ！
A jet-black rose sealed within a cage of ice!
何人の友？ ホロライブの... はかすべえるです！
Whose friend is she? Hololive's... Hakos Baelz!
Guys! I'm going to die!
Welcome to Kagura, dance with the gods! My... not really birthday, not birthday...
Birthday Live 2025! 誕生美じゃないせ、生ライブにようこそ！
Birthday Live 2025! Welcome to the live stream!
塩、塩を見たんです、今はね。
I was just watching Shio, you know.
ねえ！
Hey!
I wanted to do like a advanced-ish.
I wanted to do an advanced-ish greeting.
Hi to you guys as well. This is like the first time I get to say hi to you guys as well.
This is like the first time I get to say hi to you guys as well!
Look at the stage!
このステージ見て！
Look at this stage!
うーわ！ははっ！
Whoa! Haha!
This is my... this is my Japanese hot stage.
Wait, it's also a taiko here.
Wait, there's also a taiko here.
That's not how you play taiko! Oh my goodness.
This is the stage that I um that was especially creative for this live, because...
This is the stage that I was especially creative for this live, because...
uh the theme of today's live, I don't know if you've noticed, is um uh the aesthetics of traditional Japanese... no, that's not how it goes.
the theme of today's live, I don't know if you've noticed, is the aesthetics of traditional Japanese... No, that's not how it goes.
It's the traditional Japanese aesthetic plus dance.
ええとね、今日のライブね、テーマはね、「和」とダンスですよ。
Today's live theme is "Wa" and dance.
なんかね、そう、a lot of the songs that I may have kind of that traditional feel, ええと、clean曲というよりちょっと「和」が入ってるかなという気持ちで、あの、パフォーマンスしたいなと思ってまして、
A lot of the songs have that traditional feel, rather than clean songs, a bit more with a "Wa" feel, I wanted to perform with that feeling in mind.
I'm getting excited! There's still a lot more to come.
Please use the hashtag as well. Uh, どっち？ this one.
Please use the hashtag as well. Uh, which one? This one.
Please use the hashtag #Baedday2025.
Who knows, I might I might be gone by the end, who knows. I really don't know if I'm going to survive tonight, but
Who knows, I might be gone by the end, who knows. I really don't know if I'm going to survive tonight, but
I hope you are in the ride... oh, that's not how the saying goes.
I hope you are in the ride... that's not how the saying goes.
Wow, I actually can't talk. Hope you guys stay in this crazy ride with me until the very end.
Wow, I actually can't talk. Hope you guys stay on this crazy ride with me until the very end.
So we did Kyu-Kurarin-Pappa, I can never say that song right.
So we did Kyu-Kurarin-Pappa—I can never say that song right.
As the opening, it was so much fun with my amazing dances as usual.
I hope that was a good opener. And also, Astrogang!
For those who watched the afternoon dance, uh, dance bit, I hope, uh, if you haven't, please check it out.
For those who watched the afternoon dance bit, if you haven't, please check it out.
あの、Googleにね、ダンスリハの部もね、見てない方はぜひ見ててください。I learned the last chorus, uh, today, uh, at noon, so please watch it.
I uploaded the dance rehearsal part too, so if you haven't seen it, please check it out! I learned the last chorus today at noon, so please watch it.
I did my best! So I hope Miki-sensei is proud of me.
Yes! And you can compare how I was at, you know, the afternoon with what you just saw.
Yes! And you can compare how I was in the afternoon with what you just saw.
But this show is going to keep on going. It keeps on giving.
It is time for the very first guest. Gesto, gesto paato hairimasu. Sukitii... dare ka na?
It is time for our very first guest. Entering the guest segment! Who could it be?
Who could it be? I don't know, we'll see!
You better stay, okay? I'm going to go. Don't don't you don't you go anywhere. Okay.
心行くまで 舞い踊れ どちらがトップ 天上天下界雷 悪魔の所業め
Dance away to your heart's content, whichever is on top, high and low, thunder and lightning, the devil's work
飢えた狼 東京占め
A starving wolf takes over Tokyo
どこか寂しい 人生の寥々 散らづる煩悩のまにまに 言葉も無いや つぶやいた 惹きかす切符たの 心臓に
Somewhere lonely, life's desolation, at the mercy of scattering earthly desires, not a word to say, I murmured, handing the ticket to my heart
止まろ、あるいは、十字架。祈ったところで救いは、お気楽するドメスティックブランドを、ざっとかぎあげ、ほどせよ。
Stop, or perhaps a cross. Even if you prayed, salvation won't come. Shake off that carefree domestic brand, sniff it up quickly, and untie it.
覚醒するとしと、生憎のフェンス シェドー かんぱし全開 突き進む今日 波立つだらけの アンチモードのうえさ
As someone who awakens, unfortunately a fence, shadow, sensitivity wide open, charging straight into today, atop an anti-mode full of waves
腐れ縁つみまれ まずだって も応援、光に宿り しがみの包み、骨の限りを
Bound by an ill-fated tie, pile it up first, still cheering, dwelling in the light, wrapping the clinging, to the very bones
境界愛 しもべの心 形に鳴くとびだす心臓
Borderline love, a servant's heart, crying in shape, a leaping heart
想像すらも全部最短 愚者のまのひろは 芽を出して揺らし 超えたいのにのあてと ふらして舞え
Even imagination is all the shortest route, a fool's expanse, sprouting and swaying, wanting to surpass it, swaying and dancing toward the goal
心行くまで 舞い踊れ どちらがトップ 天上天下界雷 悪魔の所業め
Dance away to your heart's content, whichever is on top, high and low, thunder and lightning, the devil's work
飢えた狼 東京占め
A starving wolf takes over Tokyo
今宵服を脱ぎ捨てて おらする生憎のフェンス シェドー かんぱし全開 突き進む今日 波立つだらけの アンチモードのうえさ
Stripping off my clothes tonight, unfortunately a fence, shadow, sensitivity wide open, charging straight into today, atop an anti-mode full of waves
どのみち 止められぬ大好物 距離いとずらご 人よひとよで 終わらぬ愛用 良い知れぬままや 東京占め
Either way, an unstoppable favorite, distance too reluctant, people by people, love that doesn't end, unknown Tokyo takeover
中枢的都市の私 あの不夜城のショウ 再会前服と 太い足枷 ごく普通の逆戻り もっとのうえさ
Me in the central city, that sleepless city's show, pre-reunion clothes and thick shackles, returning to ordinary, even more so
不乱で生き残るため 辛らいがおおうと もしび 照らせよ我が夜を つづみねの限りを
To survive undaunted, enduring hardships, light up my night, to the limit of the drum's sound
ボクの影は プラチナになって飛び出す瞬間
My shadow turns to platinum the moment it leaps out,
想像すれば全部 最悪も何のそのわ
If you imagine it, even the worst is nothing at all.
狂おしく 揺らして
Swaying madly,
壊せない 祈りの果てへと
to the end of an unbreakable prayer.
不自然 容赦ないメトス 終了間際
Unnatural, merciless methos, right before the end,
二股に続くよ 全て吹き飛ばしちゃえ
continuing in two branches, blow everything away!
雲幕も夜空も
Both the cloud curtain and the night sky.
狂おしく 揺らして
Swaying madly,
壊せない 祈りの果てへと
to the end of an unbreakable prayer.
光れ 雷鳴へ
Shine toward the thunder!
うわあ！
Woah!
発狂しすぎた！
I went totally crazy!
すごい劇が
That was amazing...
自己紹介お願いいいですか？ はい！
Could you introduce yourself, please? Yes!
えっとうたい手としてそして
Um, as a utaite and also releasing original songs,
オリジナル曲も出したりしてる、えっとうたい手のカンカンと申しますよろしくお願いします。
I'm Kankan, a singer. Nice to meet you!
はーい！遊びに来てくれてありがとうございます。
Yay! Thank you so much for coming to hang out.
いやこちらこそありがとうございますありがとうございます！
No, thank you so much as well! Thank you!
ありがとうございますありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! Thank you!
もうもうこのままにこのまま、このままもう話そ、
Let's just stay like this... Let's just talk like this,
もう本当に、いや昔から...
really. I mean, ever since the old days...
すみませんでした！失礼しました！本当にね、
I'm so sorry! Excuse me! Really, though...
あの、もともとカンカンさんの大ファンなんで、いやありがとうございます。
I'm a huge fan of Kankan in the first place, so... Thank you so much!
今日来てくれてありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming today! Thank you so much!
あの、ちょっとま、お恥ずかしいあの話なんですけど、
Um, it's a bit embarrassing to talk about, but...
あのカンカンさんの曲を初めて聴いた時、電車中でたまたま流れたんすよ。おお！
when I first heard one of Kankan's songs, it happened to play while I was on the train. Oh!
で普通に夢中になってて、あの、降りるとこも乗りすぎました。おお！
And I was totally absorbed in it, and I actually missed my stop. Oh!
そんな夢中になって聴いてくれてたんですか？ 本当にめちゃくちゃ綺麗で
You were listening to it that engrossed? Really, it was super gorgeous...
本当に一緒にカイライ歌ってできて本当に嬉しいです。
I'm so happy we could sing "Kairai" together.
いやこちらこそ本当に、もう素敵な機械をいただいて、まさかこのカイライを選択してもらえると思ってなくて
No, I'm the one who's truly grateful. I was given such a wonderful opportunity, and I never thought you'd choose "Kairai".
まさかのチョイスなんですよ自分的に。
It was quite an unexpected choice from my end.
うわあ、でもね、あのさっきも必死で歌ったんですけど、
Woah, but you know, even though I sang so desperately earlier,
カンカンさんの声ってさもう、やばいですよ本当に！お聞きしです
Kankan's voice is just, like, insane! I'm so envious.
で、なんとカンカンさん、これもの、あの3D初登場じゃないですか？そうなんです！
And what's more, Kankan, isn't this your very first 3D appearance? That's right!
もうは、全部が初めてなんですよ今日！全部初めて！うわあ！
Everything is a first today! All of it! Wow!
そう、動き見せてくださいよ、もう。うわあ！
Show us your movements, then. Woah!
3Dどういう感じですか？カンカンもみろよ！どうどうどう、どういう感じ？
How does 3D feel? Look at Kankan! How does it feel?
ええ、やっぱりなんか普段はライブ出る時はやっぱ生身の身体で出ることが多いんですけど、
Well, usually when I perform live, I often perform in my flesh-and-blood body, but...
やっぱり全然動き方とかも違うし、全てが新感覚で！はい、ありがとうございます。
the way I move is totally different, and everything feels completely new! Yes, thank you.
いや、素晴らしい！楽しい、めちゃくちゃ！素晴らしい3D世界へようこそ！ありがとうございます！
That's wonderful! So much fun! Welcome to the wonderful 3D world! Thank you!
で、あの今回のカイライっていう歌、一緒に歌ったんですけど、カンカンさんのオリジナル曲ですよ。
And, we sang "Kairai" together this time, which is Kankan's original song.
あ、そう私のはい、ヨワネシティさんに作っていただきました。素敵な楽曲を
Ah, yes, Yowanecity-san made it for me. Such a wonderful song...
あの、まあ、歌詞がめちゃくちゃ難しいんですけど、あの、早口だし詰まってるし、リズムが大変、はい。
Um, well, the lyrics are super difficult, but it's fast, packed tight, and the rhythm is tough, yes.
です。まあちょっと、あの、意味とか曲に関してちょっと聞きたいなって思ってるんですけど、
That's right. Well, I wanted to ask a bit about the meaning and the song itself.
あーもうなんか、カイライっていうタイトルからしてもう、雷がついてるじゃないですか。もうとにかくみんなに稲妻のような衝撃を与えたいっていう気持ちからで、
Ah, well, just from the title "Kairai", it has thunder in it, right? I wanted to give everyone a shock like lightning, driven by that feeling,
ちょっとオーダーして、ヨワネシティさんに。もうヨワネシティさんならではの、やっぱり迫力ののある楽曲を作ってもらいたかったので、その結果この素敵な楽曲を作っていただいた。
so I placed an order with Yowanecity-san. I wanted a powerful song unique to Yowanecity-san, and as a result, they created this wonderful track for me.
素晴らしい。本当に、今後もね、一緒に何かコラボできてもうぜひできて本当に、あの
Wonderful. Truly, I hope we can collaborate on something together again in the future...
今日は、もう言葉が出ないやばい。どうしよう？全力で歌ったから
Today, I'm speechless, it's crazy. What should I do? I sang with all my might, so...
もうファンの気持ちはこういう感じなんだっていう、本当によかった！
So this is how fans feel! I'm so glad!
今度一緒に歌って、またできたら嬉しいとおねがいします。ありがとうございます！
I'd be so happy if we could sing together again next time. Please! Thank you!
あとみんなもね、あのカンカンさんのチャンネルとかどう、ぜひ見てください。いっぱい良い曲あるんで。
And everyone, please check out Kankan's channel too. There are lots of great songs.
いや本当に！本当、本当に寄せいただきました。本当にいい曲なんで聴いてください本当に。
Yes, really! Really, really honored to be invited. It's such a great song, please listen to it.
あと、あのOverseas fans as well, this is Kankan. Please check the channel out, they're amazing.
And for overseas fans as well, this is Kankan. Please check the channel out, they're amazing.
もう、これ本当に、カンカンがえふおーまっとからあのジェリヘットするぐらい、私はめっちゃビッグファンなので、ぜひチェックしてください。
I'm such a big fan of Kankan right now, I'm practically losing my mind, so please check them out.
はい、あの、もう、これで終わりにしたくないんだけど
Yeah, um, I really don't want it to end with this.
はい、もうね、時間があるからね、まあね、はい。
Yeah, I mean, we still have time, so, well, yeah.
ここで、いやだ、いや！
Right here? No way, no!
また今度しましょう！
Let's do it again sometime!
ぜひよろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！ ありがとうございます！
Happy birthday! Thank you very much!
Happy birthday! Thank you so much!
皆さんありがとうございました！ 乾杯でした！
Thank you everyone! Cheers!
ありがとうございました！ バイバーイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
I'm so sad! But the show must continue!
こっからまだ続きやんで、見ててね！
There's still more to come from here, so keep watching!
はい、オッケーです。行きます。
Alright, okay. Let's go.
らっしゃいな 平は成り
Welcome, peace has been restored,
時が来た 正しい
The time has come, just and right,
夢現 夜もすがら
A dream within a dream, all through the night.
変わりゆくことに 恐れなしの
With no fear of things changing,
のっぴきならないのは 御免
Being cornered like this is unacceptable.
手搏 唄 歌い 君達が 誘う
Clapping and singing, you all invite me in.
悪人に 後ろ髪 引かれても
Even if villains pull at my hair from behind,
進むべきなり
I must press forward.
流行り廃りの 憂き世なら
In this fleeting world of trends and decay,
信ずる者は ただ 君だけと
The only one I believe in is you.
踊れ騒げや 囃めや唄えや
Dance and make noise, cheer and sing,
案ずる事などないな
There's nothing to worry about.
此の世人の世は 恨めしい
This world of men is full of resentment,
雪冤は ちゃらちゃら 愛し
Vindicating the innocent with flashy affection.
蹲って 眩んで 身満創痍で
Cringing, blinded, and covered in wounds,
それ それ それ それ
Sore, sore, sore, sore!
今を嘆いて 昔を粧しても
Even if you lament the present and adorn the past,
君の心の内 流る涙川
A river of tears flows deep within your heart.
それじゃ敵わん 何処にいても
That won't do no matter where you are,
めくるめく舞台に 君を連れて
I'll take you to a dazzling, spinning stage.
あまりに長がく 一人ぞ 悲しくて
Being alone for far too long is so sad,
見放されたのが 世の ことわりか
Was being abandoned just the way of the world?
禍福離れず
Misfortune and fortune are never far apart,
郷 ざれば どく なくだえ などは
In Rome, do as the Romans do, without fail.
あらざらん 僕ら 巡り合うこと
Surely, our meeting together
まさに千載一遇
Is truly a once-in-a-lifetime chance.
吸いも甘いも 試練
The sweet and the sour are both trials,
連れ添って この手 握って
Stay by my side and hold this hand,
生きづらい 此処 浮世から
From this hard-to-survive floating world,
旗を掲げよ 宵闇が明く
Raise the banner, the evening darkness breaks!
酔いどれアガれや 寝れば忘るる
Get drunk and hyped up, sleep makes you forget,
昔も今も 変わらず
Unchanging, both in the past and today.
浮き世 飛びような げかし
Dancing lightly through the floating world,
いつだっちゅー ちゃらちゃら
Always doing it flashily,
荒んで笑って 合縁奇縁で
Smiling through the bleakness by sheer fate.
それ それ それ それ
Sore, sore, sore, sore!
深まる春も 凍てつく雪の日も
Whether in deepening spring or freezing snowy days,
日出づる すべての 瞬きを 君と見よう
Let's witness every sunrise and flicker together with you.
彩る色 何処までも
Colors adorning, no matter where we go,
空前なる 見晴らしを 眺めて
Gazing upon an unprecedented view.
未だ進む 道半ば 咎
Still halfway along the path we walk,
如何なる時も 歩を前へ出せ
Step forward no matter what time it may be.
しゃりりすったり のうきよなら
If this floating world is fleeting and unstable,
あしんずるものは ただ君だけと
The only one I believe in is you.
どれさまげや のめやうたえや あんずることなどないな
Dance and make noise, drink and sing, there's nothing to worry about!
どれさまげや のめやうたえや
Dance and make noise, drink and sing,
あんずることなどないな この世 人の世は
There's nothing to worry about in this world of men.
雪冤は ちゃらちゃら 愛し
Vindicating the innocent with flashy affection,
蹲って 眩んで 身満創痍で
Cringing, blinded, and covered in wounds.
(それ それ それ それ)
(Sore, sore, sore, sore!)
今を嘆いて 昔を粧しても
Even if you lament the present and adorn the past,
君の心の内 流る涙川
A river of tears flows deep within your heart.
それじゃ敵わん 何処にいても
That won't do no matter where you are,
めくるめく舞台に 君を連れて
I'll take you to a dazzling, spinning stage.
あまりに長がく 一人ぞ 悲しくて
Being alone for far too long is so sad,
見放されたのが 世の ことわりか
Was being abandoned just the way of the world?
禍福離れず
Misfortune and fortune are never far apart,
郷 ざれば どく なくだえ などは
In Rome, do as the Romans do, without fail.
あらざらん
Surely...
ほんものの銃弾をくらうことは少ない
Getting hit with real bullets is rare,
食料が底をつくこともあまりない
and food rarely runs out either.
路上で誰かをおなごくしてしまった
Along the way, who was it you struck down?
僕の戦場はこの胸の中に
My battlefield is inside this heart,
いつの間にか閉ざしちゃってる
closed off before I even realized.
そのドアを開けて
Open that door now...
こわれるまで とろけるまで
until it breaks, until it melts...
失うまで 戦い続ける
until it's gone, I'll keep on fighting.
手に入れたモノを手放さないと
If you're letting go of what you gained,
目を光らせてはりちらしてる
let those eyes shine to every corner.
でもきっとそうりゃ誰のもいでもない
But even so, it belongs to no one else.
僕にらむべき敵は僕の中
The enemy I should scowl at is inside me,
自分自身を守るバカ高いwall
a foolishly high wall protecting myself.
今更役に立たぬ
After all this time, it's no longer useful.
こわれるまで とろけるまで
Until it breaks, until it melts...
失うまで 戦い続ける
until it's gone, I'll keep on fighting.
日が暮れるまで 夜が明けるまで
Until day turns to night, until night turns to day...
取り戻すまで this is 魂の war
until it's retrieved, this is a war of the soul!
錆びを浴びるのが人ならざる礼儀の
If bathing in rust is the etiquette of the inhuman,
月光に隠れるのが人の形相なのは
hiding in the moonlight is taking human form—
猛がいのど真ん中の最後のなから出た
emerging right from the heart of the fierce beast's trial!
願い爆破最後まで
Wishing it explodes until the very end,
その瞳を
with those eyes...
こわれるまで とろけるまで
Until it breaks, until it melts...
失うまで 戦い続ける
until it's gone, I'll keep on fighting.
苦しみも 悲しみも
Both pain and sorrow...
抱きしめるから
I will embrace them all,
この誓いを この心を
so this oath, this heart,
あなたに捧げるのならば
if I dedicate them to you,
その命を 響かせて
let that life resonate!
この誓いを この心を
This oath, this heart,
あなたが望むのならば
if that is what you desire...
苦しみも 悲しみも 抱きしめるから
I will embrace both pain and sorrow.
抱きしめるから
I will embrace them...
ほんとつまんねえと言ってやるよこの場で
I'll tell you right here that it's totally boring,
当たり障りなくしてハズレさえも飼いとばくねど
keeping it inoffensive, taming even the misses.
それがやっぱカッコいいんだろ
That's what's so cool after all, right?
ギンギラギン
Flashy and bright!
無礼不見識な言葉でステージ上で沸かすだけ
Just hyping up the stage with rude, ignorant words.
頭の中にこびりついて取れねえ景色見せるだけ
Just showing you a view that sticks in your head.
獣並みの毛並みも並みじゃないけど何者より高く波に乗る舐めないでほしいぜ
Riding higher waves than anyone—don't underestimate me!
ネットはさながら風呂場の延長
The internet is like an extension of the bathhouse,
データの洪水 かつ日々炎上
a flood of data, daily online controversies.
石川みたいに身を入り洗浄
Purifying body and soul like Ishikawa,
一生戦場 それがなんだよ
a lifetime battlefield, so what of it?
このまま行こう
Let's keep going just like this!
どんな甘いも酸いも全部かぶりついて見せるぜ
I'll bite into every sweet and sour thing and show you.
このまま行こう
Let's keep going just like this,
どんな不満や不穏に不意に面食らっても
no matter what sudden unease or discontent hits me.
錆びた鎖じゃ意味はなさず飛び降りてから塞ぎ
Rusted chains mean nothing—jumping off and sealing it.
ギンギラギンにありのまま行く
Flashy and bright, going just as I am!
そう俺はみせるだけ 畳とメッセを得る風邪で
Yeah, I'll just show you, getting tatami and messages...
ホントつまらないって言ってやるよ この場所で
I'll tell you right here how boring it is.
当たり障りなくなくして 外れさえも欠かした賭博など
Safely losing without making waves, even missing bets...
そうずっと変わらないで 変わリ続ける 懲りずに媚びずにカマす
Staying unchanged yet ever-changing, never learning, never flattering—just striking hard.
それがやっぱりカッコいいだろ
That's still the coolest way, right?
我が身を投じる場所なら絶対
If it's a place to throw my life into, absolutely...
今この場所この舞台で決定
I've decided on this place, on this stage right now.
五右衛門みたいに かなかな絶景
Like Goemon, quite a spectacular view.
向かい風吹いたって 逆 に 乗りこなし て やる ぜ
Even if a headwind blows, I'll ride right against it.
言葉が出せぬくらい暗い時代なんて言うけど
They say it's such a dark era you can't even speak your mind...
だけど見せてやる ぶちカマしてやる
Yet I'll show you, I'll smash right through it.
俺は小賢し 性質 も 姿勢 も 知んねえ が
I don't know petty cleverness, nor proper posture or attitude.
チキな規制や時勢に背き バカげけ事 やろう ぜ
Defying timid regulations and trends, let's do something crazy.
このまま行こう どんな甘いも酸いも全部噛み食らって見せるぜ
Let's keep going just like this, I'll bite through and devour all the sweet and sour.
このまま行こう どんなスイングスイングスイング負くっても
Let's keep going just like this, no matter how much we swing and miss.
このまま行こう どうせならばやれることは全部やっていこうぜ
Let's keep going just like this, since we're at it, let's do everything we can.
このまま行こう
Let's keep going...
このまま行こう いつ の 日 に か なに もかも失っちまっても
Let's keep going just like this, even if one day we lose everything.
野暮な戯言には気も留めず
Paying no mind to unrefined gossip.
俺はこの人生も
This life of mine too...
ギンギラギンに輝かせてくだけだからな
I'll just make it shine dazzlingly bright.
ギンギラギンにありのまま行く
Going just as I am, dazzlingly bright.
えい！えい！えい！
Hey! Hey! Hey!
終わったー！終わったー！
It's over! It's over!
ってことで、二人目のゲストー！
And with that, our second guest!
一言お願いします！
Please say a word!
はいぽっぽっぽ！ほらではちかれべったりこーつのパンチをころき
Hi, poppoppo! Hora de wa chikare bettari kotsu no punch wo...
今日 今日 今日もなんだこれね え、そうだよ
Today, today, today, what is this? Yeah, that's right.
やめてちょうの乗りか、もうこっからもうこれやる、ブンブン！ぶーぽぽー！
Stop riding along, from here we're doing this, vroom vroom! Bu-popo-!
いや、始めきったパンチょ！
Man, we pulled off that punch!
いやべっちゃん、ありがちょね、呼んでくれて。
Man, bet-chan, thanks so much for inviting me.
できたよ！できたね！できたよ！できたよね！
We did it! We really did it!
ギンギラ感想はどうですか？
So, what are your thoughts on 'Gingiragin'?
いや、難しかった。
Man, it was so hard.
あの、まだ見てない方はね、昼にね一応ギリギリのダンス連やってて、そ、こばで振り作ってダンスよ。
Um, for those who haven't seen it yet, at noon we did a last-minute dance rehearsal, and we made the choreography right there on the spot.
だからもうさっきの、多分間違ってるところもあったと思うので、そこは、はい、大目に見てちょうだい。
So parts of it just now might have been wrong, so please overlook those!
すいませんにした、本当に、まあ頑張りましたよね。
We really did our best, didn't we?
はい。でも30分は、ないよ普通。いや、ほっちゃり短すぎた。ねえ？でも楽しかった！
Yeah. But 30 minutes is normally not enough. Man, it was way too short. Right? But it was fun!
よかった！え、あのね、あそこのフリ好きなの。なぬぬぬぬぬぬぬ、でゅるでゅるぽっぽっぽ、みたいな。
I'm glad! And you know, I love that part of the choreography. Nunununu... duru-duru-poppoppo, like that.
分かる分かる！めっちゃ分かる！バカ早かったけど。
I know, I know! So relatable! But it was crazy fast.
うん、いや、バカ早かったけど、これでしょう？え、それも早い！でも成功したよね？成功した！本当に嬉しい！
Yeah, it was insanely fast, but it's like this, right? That's fast too! But we succeeded, didn't we? We succeeded! I'm so happy!
いや、これもうね、あの、みんなから、なんか「バッチュワと、あの、ハクタロ一緒に踊りたーい、踊りたーい」って、めちゃくちゃリクエストもらったんで、これで満足してるかな？
Man, we got so many requests from everyone saying 'We want to see Batchua and Hakutaro dance together!', so I wonder if they're satisfied with this?
満足...すいません、大、大丈夫かな？ちゃんと踊れてたっけ？わからない。だからまあ、これからもね、本当に一緒に踊りたのって...
Satisfied... um, sorry, i-is it okay? Did we dance properly? Who knows. So well, from now on too, dancing together...
えいちょーにめまった、おもてな、ねえ、可愛いし。
Eichou ni mematta, omo-tana, ne, cute.
あーじゃあって、可愛いじゃない。可愛い。何よ？
Ah, then isn't it cute? Cute. What?
え？え？何よ？なになに、何やってるの？
Eh? Eh? What? What's going on? What are you doing?
なんでもない！何よって言ったの？何よ？何よかって。何おって聞こえた。何よ？え？聞き取ってよ！
It's nothing! What did you say 'what' for? What? What? I heard 'what o'. What? Eh? Understand what I'm saying!
もう疲れたから！疲れたよもう。もう疲れたね！はい。うわ、でも...
I'm already tired! So tired already. I'm tired! Yes. Wow, but...
多分これも僕初めてなんですよ。これね、他の人とフリを作ることも初めて。ちょうらよね？え、作ったことある？
This is probably my first time doing this too. Making choreography with someone else is also a first. Right? Eh, have you ever made one?
ホロライブ入ってから無い。おおー！だから、私人生初めて！えー！ほかの人と作ったことない。
Since joining Hololive, none. Ohh! So, it's my first time in my life! Eh?! I've never made one with someone else.
なんか恥ずかしすぎて作れなかった、元々。恥ずかしい！なんか自分の、そう、自分のアイデアをちょっと出すの恥ずかしすぎるかなって、いや、無理や。
It was too embarrassing to make, originally. Embarrassing! Putting out my own ideas felt way too embarrassing, like, no way.
これ、これわかるかなみたいな。そうそうそうそう。でもわか、も無理だったよ。うん。え、でもめっちゃかっこよかったよ。
Like, 'Would they get this?' Exactly, exactly. But it was impossible. Yeah. Eh, but it looked super cool!
ありがとうね。ばっちゅもめっちゃかっこよかったよ。
Thank you. Batchu was super cool too.
で、あの、フォロワーオーバーシーズピープル、I hope we we've gotten a lot of your messages about wanting to see us perform together, so I hope this matched, I don't know, lived up to your expectations. うむ、and if you haven't checked it out, we did do a last-minute dance rehearsal making the chorus of the choreography you just saw, and which is why we made a made a few mistakes because it was so last minute, but, まぁ！
And for overseas people, I hope we've gotten a lot of your messages about wanting to see us perform together, so I hope this lived up to your expectations. And if you haven't checked it out, we did do a last-minute dance rehearsal making the chorus of the choreography you just saw, and which is why we made a few mistakes because it was so last minute, but, well!
Please, just overlook that. Anyway.
ありがとね！
Thanks so much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとね！
Thanks so much!
べーちゃん誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday, Bae-chan!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you very much!
31歳になっちゃいましたー！
I've turned 31!
まあ、というわけでライブもね、後半入ってるので、これからもまたね、曲があるのでぜひぜひ聞いてください！
Well, the live is entering the second half, and we've got more songs coming, so please be sure to listen!
We are still, we're in like the later part of the live, so we still got a lot of songs for you guys to listen to,
We are still in the later part of the live, so we still got a lot of songs for you guys to listen to,
so please... um, I said "we", there's no one else here, this is me and staff, but I've got a lot of other songs for you to listen to, so please continue listening, thank you!
so please... I said "we", there's no one else here, but I've got a lot of other songs for you, so please continue listening, thank you!
次の曲！
Here's the next song!
Okay, let's go!
I'm going to get ready.
傷だらけの世界の頭上に
Right above a world of cuts and bruises,
闇が重くもたれかかって
darkness weighs heavily down,
覚めない時の中
within a time that never wakes.
悲しみはどこまでも追いすがって
Sorrow chases after us endlessly,
それでも空は夜明けを探して
yet still the sky searches for dawn,
取りに行く未来
to seize the future.
僕らは弱くもない儚いよ
We are not weak, yet fleeting—
信じて愛して燃え尽きて行く
believing, loving, burning out to the end.
繰り返し 繰り返し 血を流す魂が
Again and again, our bleeding souls
夢を見るその先に 輝いて 輝いて 新しい朝が来る
see dreams beyond, shining, shining, as a new morning arrives.
希望が棚引く方へ
Towards where hope flutters,
君を呼んでいる黎明へ
toward the dawn calling out your name.
失うこと 手を捨てゆくのか
Must we lose things and let go?
それとも光を追いかけるか
Or shall we chase after the light?
選んできた道に散らした
Scattered along the path we chose,
涙も傷も遠くなって
tears and scars have grown far away.
息を殺し追憶の影に焼かれて
Holding our breath, scorched by memories' shadows,
それでも鮮やかに風を切って 手に入れる未来
yet still vividly cutting through the wind to grasp the future.
情熱がいつだって灯火になるよ
Passion will always become our torchlight;
天高く上れと狼煙を上げて
raise the signal fires high into the sky.
風になり 花開き 魂を掻き鳴らす
Becoming the wind, blooming flowers, strumming our souls,
僕らが急ぐ場所へ
heading to the place we hurry to.
華やいで 華やいで 新しい朝が来る
Blooming bright, blooming bright, a new morning arrives,
光が棚引く方へ
towards where the light flutters.
夜のもう一つ向こうまで どうしても届かない手平を
Even one step beyond the night, the palm of my hand can never reach,
支えてくれる声が いつ間に こんなに響いていた
but the voices supporting me have resonated so much before I knew it.
君の行く場所に 光あれと祈った
To the place you go, I prayed for light to be there,
全ての心のため
for the sake of every heart.
繰り返し 繰り返し 血を流す魂が
Again and again, our bleeding souls
夢を見るその先に 輝いて 輝いて 新しい朝が来る
see dreams beyond, shining, shining, as a new morning arrives.
もうすぐ始まる歌 君を呼んでいる黎明へ
A song starting soon, toward the dawn calling your name...
傷だらけの世界の頭上に
Above the scarred world...
好き嫌い常識 I DON'T CARE ぶっとばせ
Likes, dislikes, conventional wisdom, I don't care, blow it all away!
混ぜこぜ MAJORITY 私に負けはない
A jumbled majority, I won't lose!
ここまでって引かないんだ その防壁だ誰のルール?
Won't back down this far, whose wall is that rule?
あの日乗り越えたウィークポイント
The weak point we overcame that day,
強くなった私があらいとばすけれど
Though the stronger me blows it away,
一体どうしよう やりたくないことをしない
What on earth should I do? Not doing what I don't want to do,
悪気気にしない 自分の時間の大前提
Not caring about malice, the premise of my own time.
あたしも変わんない ニュウノマルの時代
I'm no different either, in this new normal era.
everybody say I want to be free
譲るものも言わない その面影にも帰れない
Won't give up anything, can't return to that trace.
everybody say I want to live more
かなえたい 自分を肯定 生きてる私が
Affirming myself, I'm alive and want my dreams to come true!
アナタ描いてるアタシ
The "me" you are drawing...
生まれたその時から来ランデキタノモヨウセ
From the moment I was born, coming through emotional patterns,
アタシはアタシだ 不可能なことなど何ひとつない
I am who I am, nothing is impossible at all!
好き嫌い常識 I DON'T CARE ぶっとばせ
Likes, dislikes, conventional wisdom, I don't care, blow it all away!
するてん鳴らせ この歌詞かます 分からせ 挑発
Let it ring out, smash these lyrics, make them understand, provoke!
下向いて下打ちからのハッ
Looking down, clicking my tongue, from the bottom of my heart, hah!
足し算ずばり倍返し位フライ パッチライン 聞かせてあげる
Addition, exactly double payback, punchline, let me make you hear it!
やってから考えな アタシがついているから
Think about it after doing it, because I'm with you!
everybody say I want to be free
覚悟のビートか数えきれんじゃ 黙らせる瞬間
Beats of resolve, countless moments to silence them!
everybody say I want to live more
眠らせおきろ 描いてるアタシ
Wake up, let sleep, the "me" I'm drawing!
描いてるアタシ
The "me" I'm drawing...
生まれたその時から来ランデキタノモヨウセ
From the moment I was born, coming through emotional patterns,
アタシはアタシだ 不可能なことなど何ひとつない
I am who I am, nothing is impossible at all!
生まれたその時から来ランデキタノモヨウセ
From the moment I was born, coming through emotional patterns,
あなたはあなただ 不可能なことなど何ひとつない
You are who you are, nothing is impossible at all!
好き嫌い常識 I DON'T CARE ぶっとばせ
Likes, dislikes, conventional wisdom, I don't care, blow it all away!
Woohoo! How was that?
Bang bang bang bang bang! Oh, I feel like...
we we we did a lot of songs and I didn't really get to talk about them
we did a lot of songs and I didn't really get to talk about them
because there were other guest parts in between, but there's a couple of songs that I performed
because there were other guest parts in between, but there's a couple of songs I performed
that I've always wanted to sing. "Bang" is been is one of them so I hope you enjoyed that
that I've always wanted to sing. "Bang" is one of them, so I hope you enjoyed that!
There are still some songs I want to perform, but before that, I have two announcements.
Not one, two! And here is the first one. Ta-da!
最初は? 何が? 誕生日記念グッズ2025年 My Birthday Goods!
First is what? Birthday Commemorative Goods 2025 My Birthday Goods!
2025 even though it's not really my birthday.
Um, is looking like this.
Isn't it amazing?
Shall we have a look through them?
All right.
Can I get the first item, please?
最初のアイテムお願いします！
(Japanese spoken)
Ta-da!
Oh my goodness, look at that!
The first item we have is a...
acrylic block done by the amazing Mika Pikazo!
Mika-mama ga kaite kureta e desu yo!
(Japanese spoken)
Uwa, no kokoro janai desu ka? Uwa, is so...
It's got the, the heart of...
the Japanese? I don't really know how to say it, but...
I've always wanted an acrylic block. Um, I haven't done— I haven't made one yet, so I really hope that you display this in your homes, minna-ne, ano...
I've always wanted an acrylic block. Um, I haven't done—I haven't made one yet, so I really hope that you display this in your homes, minna-ne.
Ima made akuririku burokku wa yatta koto nai node, zehi yokattara katte mite kudasai!
(Japanese spoken)
Um, it's me dancing in a festival.
Hai.
(Japanese spoken)
Odotteru boku nan desu. Meccha chicchai.
Ano... ichio daburu... daburudee yo? Te kanji? Ajin- I don't really know how to explain it, but it's kind of like a two-layer type acrylic block,
(Japanese spoken)
so it kind of gives the image of it being 3D,
which makes it really cool.
So if you want, please get it. Ihihihihihihi, te kanji desu! Ano... hai!
So if you want, please get it. (Japanese spoken)
Ja, tsugi no aitemu onegai shimasu!
Ta-da-da-dum!
I'm so excited about this one.
The next item is the Rat Sack II Duffel bag!
Uh, this is— I wanted to create a dance bag, duffel bag, gym bag, because mine is kind of breaking, and I kind of need another one.
Uh, this is—I wanted to create a dance bag, duffel bag, gym bag, because mine is kind of breaking, and I kind of need another one.
So, I reused the design that I came up with from, I think it was like two years ago, my birthday, the very first Rat Sack, the cross-body bag, if you guys remember.
It is the same design, but just enlarged, and it has a lot of pockets, it can fit a lot of things.
And also, it's good for gym, it's good for dance, it's also good for travel.
It's really good carry-on luggage as well, cuz it's like big, it fits stuff, but not too big, you know?
And there, there's a, you know, the transparent pocket like in the— in the original cross-body bag, you can put your pins, but they won't, like, you know, get destroyed, and— and— and you can protect them and stuff like that.
And there, there's a, you know, the transparent pocket like in the—in the original cross-body bag, you can put your pins, but they won't, like, you know, get destroyed, and—and—and you can protect them and stuff like that.
Yeah. Ano, kono bagu ga meccha oki ni iri desu.
Yeah. (Japanese spoken)
Jitsu wa ne, jibun mo ne dansu bagu hoshikute tsukutta n desu yo.
(Japanese spoken)
De, nene mae no kurosu bodhi bagu mo attan desu kedo, onaji dezain de tsukutte mita n desu! Meccha ii desho?
Ne, jimu toka ryokou toka, dansu toka zenbu tsukai yasui nde zehi katte kudasai!
(Japanese spoken)
Um, yeah.
And then, next item, tsugi no aitemu onegai shimasu.
And then, next item, (Japanese spoken)
Woo! I finally did it, guys, made the DripTaro necklace.
Yeah, I really like this kind of style of necklaces, and I've always wanted to make one, and now I did! Look at, there's so many little— like, there's so many different parts to it, like the— the tag and the dice and the cross.
Yeah, I really like this kind of style of necklaces, and I've always wanted to make one, and now I did! Look at, there's so many little—like, there's so many different parts to it, like the—the tag and the dice and the cross.
It's just very drip.
Ne, kakkoii nekkuresu jibun mo meccha konomi de ano tsukutte mita. Zehi katte mite kudasai!
(Japanese spoken)
De, tsugi! Onegai shimasu.
Next we have the full set bonus.
Kochira wa ne, it is, um, exclusively available for those who buy the full set.
(Japanese spoken)
Furu setto desu ka? Ano maenai yatsu nan de, ano...
Ne, you can put it onto the bag, boku ni tsuke raremasu toka ne, moshiyokattara onegai shimasu! De, tsugi wa motto, tsugi onegai shimasu!
(Japanese spoken)
Tsugi wa ne, this is...
Oh, so, you know, full set, um, I'm not signing every single one this time.
I'm sorry, my arm is literally going to fall off.
So, uh, there is a limited, uh, edition where you do get a hand-signed, uh, postcard by me, if, you know, there is a limited number, so please do check it out after the live.
Ano... konkai wa ne, j- jiki chokusai wa suuryou gentei dakara, raibu owattara ano zehi minna katte ne! Konkai wa ne zenbu sain dekinakute hontoni sumimasen. Mou ude ga mou owatteru nde, sumimasen. Hai!
(Japanese spoken)
And I think we have one more thing, more— t- one more thing, nanka arimasu yo ne? Tsugi onegai shimasu.
And I think we have one more thing, more—t-one more thing, (Japanese spoken)
Um, this is actually very special.
This is hasn't happened before, but if you do fi- the buy the full set, there is an extra bonus as well.
This is hasn't happened before, but if you do fi-the buy the full set, there is an extra bonus as well.
It is one card that can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game. This is the special Oshi Holomem card exclusively available if you buy the full set.
So if you haven't played yet, you can check out the card details. Make sure you know how to play on the Hololive Official Card Game homepage.
So please be sure to take a look. You get Mika-mama's amazing art on one of the cards.
But yeah, s-ano ne, hajimete kādo gêmu no yō na kādo mo ano furu setto katte kureru kata ni
(Japanese spoken)
ある、ありそうなんで、是非みんな買って、ください！はい！
It seems like it'll be available, so please everyone buy it! Yes!
ということで、
So,
That is my birthday celebration 2025 merch! イェーイ！
That is my birthday celebration 2025 merch! Yay!
みんなに買ってね、お願いします。
Please everyone buy it, I'm asking you.
Now, I said there were two announcements.
That was one. I wonder what two is.
なんでしょう？
What is it?
What is the second announcement?
Maybe I can give you idea, but first, I want you to listen to this last song!
Maybe I can give you an idea, but first, I want you to listen to this last song!
Wild hunger out of control,
Miss Rat Born Queen, 壊してそう決処
Miss Rat, Born Queen, destroy and execute everything,
咲き誇れ狂え
Go mad, bloom in full glory!
SECRET それもしょーさんのDIRECT!
SECRET! That's also Shosan's DIRECT!
咲くわ咲くらい おみさんごちらてのごなるほえ
Blooming, blooming so darkly, look at us clapping our hands in unison,
もう誰も止められない
No one can stop us anymore!
Don't stop 暴れ狂おう
Don't stop, let's rampage wildly!
獰猛狂暴！その胸突き出して、愛が害なら離せないモード
Ferocious and violent! Thrust out your chest, if love is harm, we're in a mode we can't let go.
飢えた野性、叫べ、吠えろ！
Starved wildlife, scream, look!
飢えた野性 叫べ 吠えろ
Starved wildlife, scream, howl!
ざわめき放つ衝動 その鼓動が胸を刺すくらい
Impulse releasing a murmur, to the extent that the heartbeat pierces the chest,
狂おしいほどの快楽 HEAD SHOT!
Pleasure so mad, HEAD SHOT!
そう正解、正解、狂え狂え、見せかけの狂気や顔も
That's right, exactly right, go mad, even fake madness and expressions,
同的感情、正解、迷い、どれあれ、この衝動
dynamic emotions, correctness, hesitation, whatever it is, this impulse,
抑えきれない、感情を突き出して、狂おしいほど狂いそう
Uncontainable, thrusting out emotions, feeling like going crazy with madness.
そう正解、正解、狂え狂え、見せかけの狂気や顔も、同的感情、正解、迷い、どれあれ
That's right, exactly right, go mad, even fake madness and expressions, dynamic emotions, correctness, hesitation, whatever it is,
妄想死ぬほど狂え！狂宴-FEAST-
Delusions, go mad until you die! Feast!
さあ、狂わず目突き出して、さあ、狂い狂いに飢えて
Come on, thrusting out chest without going crazy, coming on, starving for madness,
Don't stop 狂わせろ、その純度
Don't stop, drive them wild, that purity!
獰猛狂暴、狂えるほどの感情、喉元に爪を突き立てて
Ferocious and violent, emotions to the point of going crazy, sinking claws into the throat,
誰にも求められない
No one can demand it anymore!
歪む視界、演歌衝動、狂気で狂う感情
Distorted field of view, enka impulse, emotions driven mad by madness,
もう誰にも邪魔できない HEAD SHOT!
No one can get in our way anymore, HEAD SHOT!
そう正解、正解、狂え狂え、見せかけの狂気や顔も
That's right, exactly right, go mad, even fake madness and expressions,
同的感情、正解、迷い、どれあれ、この衝動
dynamic emotions, correctness, hesitation, whatever it is, this impulse,
抑えきれない感情を突き出して、狂おしいほど狂いそう
Uncontainable emotions thrusting out, feeling like going crazy with madness,
そう正解、正解、狂え狂え、見せかけの狂気や顔も
That's right, exactly right, go mad, even fake madness and expressions,
同的感情、正解、迷い、どれあれ、妄想死ぬほど狂え！
dynamic emotions, correctness, hesitation, whatever it is, delusions, go mad until you die!
盲目に突き刺せ、乱れる魂、踊り明かす本能、さあ、進もうぜ！
Blindly pierce, swirling soul, instincts dancing through the night, come on, let's go!
違いを分かつのさ、さあ、遊びましょう！
Sharing our differences, come on, let's play!
ああ、大親展の、大親展！あ、the second announcement is a new song!
Ah, a big announcement, a big announcement! Ah, the second announcement is a new song!
新曲でます。どうだった？ How was it?
A new song is coming out. How was it?
This is what you heard, da-da-da-da-da-da-dum, 狂宴!
This is what you heard, da-da-da-da-da-da-dum, Kyōen!
Oh my god. That's crazy. I it's I know. It's been a while.
I said I was going to go back to making music and I I I kind of dabbled a little bit, you know, not anything too crazy, but
I have a new single called Feast, 狂宴. It is produced by the amazing biz and Zera-san. BizとZeraさんのあの作ってくれた曲なんで
I have a new single called Feast, Kyōen. It is produced by the amazing biz and Zera-san.
please have a look it's it's so I bow. It's so cool.
Please check it out, it's so—I bow. It's so cool.
Um I want to be as cool as her. Can I be as cool as her? Is like this? No, doesn't work.
Anyway, um this is my new song and um it is the MV is also coming out after the live, so please check it out.
Anyway, um this is my new song and um the MV is also coming out after the live, so please check it out.
The art is done by the masterful Diner as always. Look at that look at that art. And on live, MVも公開するのでぜひ見ててください。
The art is done by the masterful Diner as always. Look at that, look at that art. And the MV will be released right after the live, so please be sure to check it out.
今回のアートもね、ダイノ先生が書いてくれて、さったので、本当にすごいMVになったと思います。And um, I did the dance. It's it's kind of concerning when, you know, your original song, you feel like the dance is is is is not as hard as other ones that I did this time, but it
The art this time was also drawn by Diner-sensei, so I think it turned out to be a really amazing MV. And um, I did the dance...
really is really fun as well, so
It really is really fun as well, so
I'll be doing, I'll be uploading like shorts and stuff as well.
I'll be uploading like shorts and stuff as well.
Um I wanted to, you know, embody the beast.
So please check that out as well.
And yeah. Am I forgetting anything?
Oh yeah! Streaming services!
On the Heisenet, the streaming services is going to start at midnight.
On the Heisenet, the streaming services are going to start at midnight.
Time, if you ask me, time zone, I have no idea.
As, as usual, I don't have any idea about anything.
As usual, I don't have any idea about anything.
But I'm told it is midnight at, uh, tonight.
But I'm told it is midnight tonight.
It'll be out! Just have a listen to it when it's out. Thank you very much.
Um, but that's it.
Is that it? Did I do it?
How was the live? How, how are you doing?
You're doing okay? Everything, everyone doing okay?
You're doing okay? Everyone's doing okay?
どうだった? 今日のライブ。大丈夫だった?
How was today's live? Was it okay?
Did I do good? I hope I did okay.
Um, I still want to hear all your thoughts after live I'm going to have a, you know, long look at the hashtag BaeDDay2025.
Um, I still want to hear all your thoughts after the live. I'm going to have a long look at the hashtag #BaeDDay2025.
So, um, thank you so much for watching as always. This year I really wanted to focus on dance,
So thank you so much for watching as always. This year I really wanted to focus on dance,
so, um, I hope, you know, that got across.
so I hope that got across.
でもね、やっぱりダンスもっと頑張りたいなと思ってるんで、
But you know, I really want to work harder at dancing, so
今日のライブで ちょっとそれ あの、伝えれてるかなって、伝ってるかなって、あの、ちょっと、まあ、今ね、伝わったらいいなって思ってます。
in today's live, I wanted to convey that... I hope it got across to everyone.
But I guess that's it! I'm going to go die now.
I'm so tired. The words exiting my mouth are just gone. I have no idea, nothing's happening up here.
But, um, I will continue to work hard. Thank you so much for a not birthday birthday this year.
But I will continue to work hard. Thank you so much for a not-birthday birthday this year.
Um, it was a little different for Baeberry, but I guess that's the end of Baeberry. What was Baeberry? Who knows?
It was a little different for Baeberry, but I guess that's the end of Baeberry. What was Baeberry? Who knows?
But that's it for today! Thanks for coming! Sticker Datteba-yo! Matakondo ne! Bye! Bye! Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
Thank you for watching I survived!!
All your support means the world to me ㅠ ㅠ
All your support means the world to me!
支えてくれた本当にありがとう
Thank you so much for your support.
your support made this the best NON-bday bday ever!!
Your support made this the best non-birthday birthday ever!!
これからもがんばるよね
I'll keep doing my best!